Michał Wadowski

Senior Java Developer

Michał is software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. He has been working in Java oriented projects for over 4 years using Spring Boot technologies. He values clean code, TDD and other good programming practices.

Professional experience

Mindbox S.A.

HSBC Service Delivery (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

08.2022 - 06.2024

Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" internal business application in Java 8, 11, 17 using Spring Boot in microservices architecture. PostgreSQL/Oracle, ReactJS and Jenkins was

also used in project.

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

02.2022 - 07.2022

Developing microservices for streaming platform using Kafka, MongoDB and Java

Reactor

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

02.2021 - 07.2022

Developing Eclipse Leshan library https://www.eclipse.org/leshan for IoT communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The City using Spring Boot and PostgreSQL technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

Android Developer

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians using Live Objects platform

https://liveobjects.orange-business.com with Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages. As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

06.2014 - 02.2020

Full-stack Developer

Developing https://awanser.pl business

platform using technologies:

Backend: PHP and CakePHP framework,

PostgreSQL database system Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6, CSS, LESS and SCSS

Contact

Address

Warsaw, Poland

Phone

+48 796 334 459

F-mail

wadosm@amail.com

Github

https://github.com/Michal-Wadowski

Experience and knowledge

Programming languages / technologies

Java: Spring Boot, JUnit, Hibernate, Lombok, Java Reactor, Kafka

Databases

PostgreSQL/pgSQL, Oracle, MongoDB

Other tools

Maven, GIT, Docker compose, Jenkins

Good practices

TDD, DDD, Clean architecture, software design patterns

IDE

IntelliJ IDEA

Operating systems

Linux, Windows

Software Development Model

SCRUM

Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

Javasript: ECMAScript 6, JSX, ReactJS,

Redux, ¡Query

Python: NUMPY, Keras

C, C++

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o.

Java Developer

Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o.

Software Developer

Developing of business application in Delphi and, PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o.

Full-stack Developer

Developing internet application for HACCP

Javascript, jQuery, MySQL

management in technologies: Ruby on Rails,

Training

March 2022 Professional Scrum Developer

L (PSD 1)

Education

2009 - 2011 University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn
 Field of study: Computer science
 M. Sc.
 2005 - 2008 University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn
 Field of study: Computer systems
 Undergraduate course

Courses

Creating µServices using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Spring Framework II

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Test-Driven Development in practice

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Useful characteristics

Writing good quality code

Experienced in working with legacy systems

IT technologies quick learner

Teamwork skills

Independence and responsibility

Languages

Polish

Native

English

В2

Passions & hobbies

Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits

Building and training artificial neural networks

Developing applications and devices for own needs

Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general